根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
《权力的游戏》第四季 第四集
《守誓之剑》
我的名字
My name
是灰虫子
is Grey Worm.
我来自
I come from
盛夏“群刀”
the Summer "Ills."
群岛
Isles.
盛夏群岛
Summer Isles.
我来自纳斯岛
I am from an island called Naath.
你什么时候带走的？
When they took you?
我什么时候被带走的？
"When did they take me?"
我五岁的时候
I was five years old.
你还记得你家吗？
You remember your home?
我记得他们从海边袭击我们
I remember when they rowed us away from shore.
记得沙滩有多白
How white the beaches were.
树有多高
How tall the trees.
我还记得村子在燃烧
And I remember my village burning.
浓烟升到空中
Smoke rising into the sky.
你还记得你家吗？
Do you remember your home?
无垢者
Unsullied.
一直都是无垢者
Always Unsullied.
成为无垢者之前，什么也不记得
Before Unsullied, nothing.
这不是真的
That's not true.
也许有一天你会回到盛夏群岛
Perhaps one day you will return to the Summer Isles.
我不想回去
I don't want return.
杀死奴隶主
Kill the masters.
教得怎么样了？
How are the lessons coming?
非常好，陛下
Very well, Your Grace.
弥桑黛是老师好，女王
Missandei is teacher good, my queen.
以后再继续吧
You'll have to continue later.
该出发了
It's time.
你们听见她的话了
她说她是来解放我们的！
别犯傻了，主人太强大了
她会保护我们
她打败了主人的勇士
她有庞大的军队
你们想带着镣铐活一辈子吗？
我想活着，你看他们是怎样对那些孩子的
你觉得他们会怎样对我们？
我经历过两次奴隶叛乱，孩子
结果都一样
主人掌权，奴隶死去
凡人皆有一死
但我保证
一天自由胜过一生枷锁
你是谁？
我叫灰虫子
我婴儿时就被阿斯塔波的奴隶主带走了
被训练成为无垢者
现在，我为丹妮莉丝而战，她是龙之母
是奴隶解放者
你是无垢者？
你还不会走时就开始接受战斗训练了
可我们不是战士
我们没受过训练
没有武器
这个城里每个奴隶主有三个奴隶
没人能给你你的自由，兄弟们
如果你想要，就自己争取
杀死奴隶主
弥莎！弥莎！弥莎！
Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa!
弥莎！弥莎！弥莎！弥莎！
Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa!
弥莎！弥莎！
Mhysa! Mhysa!
乔拉爵士，提醒我下
Remind me, Ser Jorah,
伟主们在里程标上钉了多少孩子？
how many children did the Great Masters nail to mileposts?
163个，卡丽熙
163, Khaleesi.
对，是的
Yes, that was it.
陛下，能单独谈谈吗？
Your Grace, may I have a word?
这座城是您的了
The city is yours.
所有这些人，现在都是你的臣民
All these people, they're your subjects now.
有时用仁慈对待不公
Sometimes it is better to answer injustice
会更好
with mercy.
我会用公正对待不公
I will answer injustice with justice.
这算什么招？
What the hell was that?
这招叫用你自己的手把你…
That was me knocking your ass to the dirt
揍倒在地
with your own hand.
你真是稀世天才
You're a rare talent.
用这种招数对战残疾人
When you're fighting cripples, anyway.
你学的都是正派打法
You learned to fight like a good little boy.
我敢说从后背刺穿疯王
I'll bet that thrust through the Mad King's back
那画面肯定漂亮
was pretty as a picture.
你是想打得漂亮还是想打赢？
You want to fight pretty or you want to win?
你跟我弟弟也这么说话？
You talk to my brother this way?
一直都是
All the time.
他都习惯了
He got used to it.
你认为是他干的吗？
Do you think he did it?
不
No.
他确实痛恨那个小混蛋
Oh, he hated the little twat, sure.
可谁不恨呢
But who didn't?
下毒也不是他的作风
And poison's not his style.
他不会谋杀
Or murder, for that matter.
你想确定的话，为什么不亲自问他？
You want to know for sure, why don't you ask him?
你还没见过他，是吗？
You haven't been to see him yet, eh?
今天就到这吧
We're done for today.
你弟弟有没有说过我怎么会为他效力的？
Your brother ever tell you how I came into his service?
你在鹰巢城帮他赢了比武审判
You stood for him in his trial by combat at the Eyrie.
是的
Aye.
但只是因为艾琳夫人要求
But only when Lady Arryn demanded
审判必须那天举行
the trial take place that day.
他首先选的是你
You were his first choice.
他选了你帮他决斗
He named you for his champion
因为他知道你会日夜兼程
because he knew you would ride day and night
赶来为他而战
to come fight for him.
这次你要为他而战吗？
You gonna fight for him now?
说实话，这不算很糟了
To tell you the truth, this isn't so bad.
四面有墙，有尿壶
Four walls. A pot to piss in.
我被锁在一个木栏里
I was chained to a wooden post
几个月来拉撒都在里面
covered in my own shit for months.
你是想让我好受些么？
Is that supposed to make me feel better?
有一点吧
Maybe a bit.
抱歉我没有早点来
I'm sorry I didn't come sooner.
事情很复杂，我知道
It's complicated, yes.
- 那我们的姐姐到底如何了？ - 你觉得呢？
- So how is our sister? - How do you think?
她的儿子死在她怀里
Her son died in her arms.
她的儿子？
Her son?
别这样
Don't.
你知道接下来会怎样吗？
You know what's coming?
我要因弑君被审判，我知道
My trial for regicide. Yes, I know.
我知道整个国家都他妈认为我有罪
I know the whole bloody country thinks I'm guilty.
我知道我的三位法官之一
I know that one of my three judges
早就无数次希望我死了
has wished me dead more times than I can count.
这位法官就是我父亲
And that judge is my father.
至于瑟曦
As for Cersei,
她可能正在想方设法
well, she's probably working on a way
能不经审判就杀了我
to avoid a trial altogether by having me killed.
既然你提了，她确实求过我
Now that you mention it, she did ask.
那我是不是该转身闭上眼了？
So, should I turn around and close my eyes?
不一定
Depends.
是你干的吗？
Did you do it?
弑君者兄弟
The Kingslayer brothers.
你喜欢吗？我挺喜欢的
You like it? I like it.
你真要问我有没有杀你儿子吗？
You're really asking if I killed your son?
你真要问我该不该杀我弟弟吗？
Are you really asking if I'd kill my brother?
我怎么能帮你？
How can I help you?
你可以放我走啊
Well, you could set me free.
你知道我不能
You know I can't.
那就真没什么好说的了
Then there's really nothing else to say.
你想让我怎样？杀掉守卫？
What do you want me to do? Kill the guards?
把你藏在马车后面偷偷出城？
Sneak you out of the city in the back of a cart?
我是御林铁卫的队长
I'm the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
抱歉，我都忘了
Sorry, I'd forgotten.
我应该讨厌你做出格的事
I'd hate for you to do something inappropriate.
出格？
Inappropriate?
你被控谋杀国王，放走你是叛国罪
You're accused of killing the king. Freeing you is treason.
可是我没杀
Except I didn't do it.
所以才会有审判啊
Which is why we're having a trial.
审判
A trial.
就算凶手自己滚到铁王座前
If the killer threw himself before the Iron Throne,
承认罪行
confessed to his crimes,
并拿出铁证证明
and gave irrefutable evidence of his guilt,
瑟曦也不在乎
it wouldn't matter to Cersei.
她不看我人头落地是不会罢休的
She won't rest until my head's on a spike.
不只是你
Not just yours.
她悬赏爵士封号给任何抓到珊莎·史塔克的人
She's offering a knighthood to whomever finds Sansa Stark.
不可能是珊莎干的
Sansa couldn't have done this.
她比七大王国里任何人都有动机
She had more reason than anyone in the Seven Kingdoms.
你觉得在乔佛里死去当晚
Do you think it's a coincidence
她就失踪了，会是巧合？
she disappeared the same night Joffrey died?
不，但是…
No, but...
珊莎不会杀人
Sansa's not a killer.
反正现在不会
Not yet, anyway.
你要带我去哪？
Where are you taking me?
我要娶你姨妈莱莎
I'm getting married to your Aunt Lysa.
她正在鹰巢城等我们
She's waiting for us at the Eyrie.
你到那就安全了
You'll be safe there.
是你杀了乔佛里吗？
Did you kill Joffrey?
是我杀了乔佛里吗？
Did I kill Joffrey?
几个星期来我一直在谷地
I've been in the Vale for weeks.
我知道是你
I know it was you.
那是谁帮我完成这阴谋呢？
And who helped me with this conspiracy?
有唐托斯爵士
Well, there was Ser Dontos.
你利用他带我离开君临
You used him to get me out of King's Landing,
但你不可能信任他去杀国王
but you would never trust him to kill the king.
为什么？
Why not?
因为你是聪明人，不会信任酒鬼
Because you're too smart to trust a drunk.
那也许是你丈夫
Then perhaps it was your husband.
不是
No.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我就是知道
I just do.
你说对了
You're right.
他与乔佛里之死无关
He wasn't involved in Joffrey's death.
但你有关
But you were.
你还记得唐托斯送你的那条漂亮项链吗？
Do you remember that lovely necklace Dontos gave you?
我猜你没注意到婚宴之后
I don't suppose you noticed that a stone was missing
少了块宝石
after the feast.
是毒药
The poison.
我不懂
I don't understand.
兰尼斯特家给了你财富，权力
The Lannisters gave you wealth, power.
乔佛里封你为赫伦堡领主
Joffrey made you the Lord of Harrenhal.
没有动机就没人怀疑
A man with no motive is a man no one suspects.
要不停迷惑敌人
Always keep your foes confused.
如果他们不知道你是谁或你想要什么
If they don't know who you are or what you want,
他们就无法预料你的下一步计划
they can't know what you plan to do next.
我不信
I don't believe you.
如果他们抓住你 他们会把你的头插上枪尖
If they catch you, they'll put your head on a spike
就像我父亲那样
just like my father's.
你会冒如此风险，只为迷惑他们？
You'd risk that just to confuse them?
许多人不愿冒风险
So many men, they risk so little.
一辈子躲避危险
They spend their lives avoiding danger.
然后死去
And then they die.
我愿冒任何风险去得到我想要的
I'd risk everything to get what I want.
你想要什么？
And what do you want?
全部
Everything.
我与兰尼斯特家的交情收获颇丰
My friendship with the Lannisters was productive.
但乔佛里
But Joffrey,
头戴王冠的凶残小孩
a vicious boy with a crown on his head,
不是可靠的同盟
is not a reliable ally.
谁能信任那样的朋友？
And who could trust a friend like that?
谁能信任你？
Who could trust you?
我不想要我这样的朋友
I don't want friends like me.
我的新朋友言出必行
My new friends are predictable.
通情达理
Very reasonable people.
至于乔佛里的遭遇
As for what happened to Joffrey,
那是我的新朋友迫切想要的
well, that was something my new friends wanted very badly.
没有什么能像一份贴心的礼物
Nothing like a thoughtful gift
增进新的友谊
to make a new friendship grow strong.
不敢相信你要走
I can't believe you're going.
让我一人和这些人在一起
Leaving me alone here with these people.
是时候了，亲爱的
The time has come, my dear.
没有什么比审判更无趣的了
There's nothing more tedious than a trial.
也许除了这些花园
Except perhaps these gardens.
如果让我在这些花园里
If I have to take one more leisurely stroll
再逛一次，我就跳崖
through these gardens, I'll fling myself from the cliffs.
你见过托曼了吗？
Have you been to see Tommen yet?
没有
No.
他们同意婚事了吗？
Have they even agreed to the match?
没人告诉我任何事
No one tells me anything.
我最初不是…
I wasn't originally meant
要嫁给你祖父罗斯的
to marry your grandfather Luthor, you know.
他跟我姐姐订了婚
He was engaged to my sister,
你姨婆维奥拉
your great-aunt Viola.
我本来要嫁给坦格利安的
I was to be given to some Targaryen or other.
当时嫁给坦格利安很流行
Marrying a Targaryen was all the rage back then.
但当我看到我未婚夫
But the moment I saw my intended,
狰狞的白鼬脸
with his twitchy little ferret's face
和可笑的银发时
and ludicrous silver hair,
我就知道我不能嫁给他
I knew he wouldn't do.
所以到了晚上
So the evening
罗斯向我姐姐求婚前
before Luthor was to propose to my sister,
我上完刺绣课在回来的路上迷路了
I got lost on my way back from my embroidery lesson
偶然到了他的卧室
and happened upon his chamber.
我太不小心了
- How absentminded of me. - Mm-hmm.
第二天早上，罗斯下不了楼梯
The following morning, Luthor never made it down the stairs
不能向我姐姐求婚，因为他走不了路
to propose to my sister 'cause the boy couldn't bloody walk.
一旦他能走路了，他就只想要
And once he could, the only thing he wanted
我前一晚给他的
was what I'd given him the night before.
我很棒
I was good.
我非常棒
I was very, very good.
你更棒
You are even better.
但你得赶紧行动
But you need to act quickly.
瑟曦也许恶毒，但她不傻
Cersei may be vicious, but she's not stupid.
她很快就会让那个男孩对付你
She'll turn the boy against you as soon as she can.
等你结婚就晚了
And by the time you're married, it'll be too late.
所幸摄政太后
Luckily for you, the Queen Regent
现在分了心
is rather distracted at the moment.
悼念他死去的宝贝儿子
mourning her dear departed boy.
指责他弟弟是凶手
Accusing her brother of his murder,
但他不是
which he didn't commit.
他本来可以那么做
Well, he could have done.
他可以，但他没有那么做
He could have done, but he didn't.
- 你不知道，祖母 - 但我的确知道
- You don't know, Grandmother. - But I do know.
你不会觉得我会把你嫁给那个恶魔吧？
You don't think I'd let you marry that beast, do you?
什么？我不明白
What? I don't understand.
嘘，你别担心
Shh. Don't you worry yourself about all that.
你只需做你需要做的
You just do what needs to be done.
穿过来！
Bring it through!
再来
And again.
很好，不错
Very nice. Good.
很多野人作战时两手都有武器
A lot of wildlings fight with a weapon in each hand.
你们首先要做的
First thing you want to do
卸了他们的武器，尽量跟他们势均力敌
is disarm them to try and even the odds.
看看你们能做什么
Let's see what you can do.
奥利, 你现在就看看吧
Olly, you just watch for now.
我能打
I can fight.
你以前拿过剑吗？
Have you ever held a sword before?
我在我们村是最好的弓箭手
I was the best archer in our hamlet.
真的啊！
I was!
我相信你
I believe you.
改天我们打野兔去
We'll go hunting for rabbits one day.
现在看着学习一下
Rit now, watch and learn.
你们俩
You two.
慢慢来，试着卸了对方的武器
Take it slow, try and disarm each other.
你会打斗
You know how to fight.
不需要那么较真
You could have gone easier on him.
那样他就学不到东西
He wouldn't have learned anything that way.
雪诺大人
你在干什么？
What do you think you're doing?
我跟葛兰在帮他们
Grenn and I were helping them.
葛兰是游骑兵，你是事务官
Grenn's a ranger. You're a steward.
也许你忘了你跟野人婊子搞在一起过
Maybe you forgot that while you were off with your wildling bitch,
我可没忘
but I didn't.
必须有人训练他们
Someone has to train them.
那人不是你
And that someone isn't you.
去看看有没有夜壶要倒
Go find a chamber pot to empty.
快点，去啊
Go on. Do it.
你这个叛国者的私生子
You traitor's bastard.
别给我机会
Give me an excuse.
这里没有莫尔蒙保护你
Mormont's not here to protect you now.
回去干活
Get back to work.
快点！
Now!
我说快点！
I said now!
那个私生子很受欢迎，你则不然
The bastard's well-liked. You're not.
你认为我在乎他们是否喜欢我？我们在打仗
You think I care if they like me? We're at war.
暂时是
For now.
但你不可能永远做指挥
But you can't be acting commander forever.
要选一个
There will be a choosing.
老学士会坚持如此
The old maester will insist on it.
你可以重新考虑…
You might reconsider
进军卡斯特的要求
his request to march on Craster's.
让反叛者干掉雪诺
Let the mutineers take care of Snow.
否则你的余生都将听从
Or you might be taking orders from him
他的指令
the rest of your life.
私生子，嗯？
A bastard, eh?
以为你是贵族
Took you for highborn.
我父亲是贵族
My father was highborn.
我母亲不是
My mother wasn't.
我叫洛克
Name's Locke.
琼恩·雪诺
Jon Snow.
你身手不错
You fight well.
你怎么来这里的？
What brought you up here?
责任感
A sense of duty.
我想为保证王国安全献一份力
I wanted to do my part for the safety of the realm.
我在风暴地是一名护猎员
I was a game warden in the Stormlands.
把一只昂贵的山鹑给我饥饿的孩子吃了
Fed a prized partridge to my hungry kids.
我这么蠢活该被抓
I was stupid enough to get caught.
选了来长城而不是砍手
Chose the Wall over losing my hand.
想着在这里不用巴结出生高贵的王八蛋
Figured I wouldn't have to suck up to any highborn cunts here.
快点，干活啊
Come on, get on with it.
你在等什么，夏天？
What are you waiting for? Summer?
我想错了
Guess I was wrong.
您找我，殿下？
You sent for me, Your Grace?
殿下
Your Grace.
你真规矩
How formal of you.
托曼门外有多少国王守卫守着？
How many Kingsguards are posted outside Tommen's door?
柏洛斯爵士今晚值夜
Ser Boros is on duty tonight.
- 明天我相信… - 所以只有一个人？
- Tomorrow I believe-- - So one?
你只派了一个人保护未来的国王？
You have one man guarding the future king?
我向你证托曼是安全的
I promise you Tommen's safe.
我们在保护他
We're protecting him.
就像保护乔佛里？
The way you protected Joffrey?
凯特琳·史塔克为什么放了你？
Why did Catelyn Stark set you free?
- 什么？ - 我想了几个月
- What? - I've been wondering for months.
自从那头母牛带你回到都城
Ever since that great cow brought you back to the capital.
她为什么放了你？
Why did she set you free?
你知道为什么
You know why.
她希望我放她的女儿们回去
She'd hoped I'd send her daughters back to her.
是她希望还是你答应了？
She hoped or did you promise?
我向诸神起誓
I swore by all the gods
只要她的女儿们还活着，我一定把她们还给她
that if her daughters were alive, I'd return them to her.
所以你向敌人起了神圣的誓言
So you made a sacred vow to the enemy.
我想回到你身边
I wanted to get back to you.
我应该叫她滚吗？
Should I have told her to fuck off?
那你不是真心的？
You didn't mean it, then?
你没有效忠于凯特琳·史塔克？
You have no loyalty to Catelyn Stark?
凯特琳·史塔克已经死了
Catelyn Stark's dead.
那如果我让你离开都城去找珊莎
So if I told you to leave the capital right now and find Sansa,
如果我让你找到那个凶残的小贱人
if I told you to find that murderous little bitch
把她的人头带来
and bring me her head,
你愿意吗？
would you do it?
我知道你去见提利昂了
I know you went to see Tyrion.
那个畜生杀了我们的儿子
That creature who murdered our son.
我必须见他
I had to see him.
我必须自己搞清楚
I had to know for myself.
然后呢？
And?
不是他干的，瑟曦
He didn't do it, Cersei.
你一直都同情他
You've always pitied him.
我们可怜的弟弟
Our poor little brother.
被全世界虐待
Abused by the world.
被他父亲和姐姐嫌弃
Despised by his father and sister.
要是可以，他会把我们都杀了
He'd kill us all if he could.
我要四个人日夜守护在托曼门外
I want four men at Tommen's door day and night.
就这些，指挥官大人
That will be all, Lord Commander.
突击爵士？
Ser Pounce?
你怎么通过御林守卫的？
How did you get past the Kingsguard?
御林守卫
Kingsguard.
我认为你不该来这里
I don't think you're supposed to be here.
母亲不允许我有夜间访客
Mother doesn't allow me to have visitors at night.
我不是访客，陛下
I'm not a visitor, Your Grace.
据说，我会是你的新娘
Word has it I'm to be your bride.
你知道吗，包办婚姻的两个人…
Did you know that people in arranged marriages
结婚之前都没见过？
often never meet until their wedding day?
在我们决定共度一生之前…
Before we decide to spend our lives together,
我们应该互相了解
we ought to get to know one another.
你觉得呢？
Don't you think?
是的
Yes.
可是如果母亲发现…
But if my mother found out--
这是我们的秘密，嗯？
It can be our secret. Hmm?
如果我们要成为夫妻…
If we're going to be man and wife,
我希望，能有些秘密不让她知道
we'll have a few secrets from her, I hope.
所以，陛下…
So, Your Grace...
什么？
Yes?
告诉我一个秘密
Tell me a secret.
你好，真是个好小伙？
Hello. Aren't you a proper fellow?
这是突击爵士
That's Ser Pounce.
真漂亮
Very handsome.
乔佛里不喜欢他
Joffrey didn't like him.
他威胁要活剥他的皮…
He threatened to skin him alive
把他的内脏拌到我的饭里
and mix his innards up in my food
所以我就不知道我吃了他
so I wouldn't know I was eating him.
真残忍
That's very cruel.
你没有让我觉得残忍
You don't strike me as cruel.
没有
No.
我觉得我不是
I don't think I am.
那我就放心了
That's a relief.
因为，你知道我们结婚后会怎样吗？
Because you know what happens when we marry?
我们会在总主教面前宣誓
We say our vows in front of the high septon.
仪式之后是宴会…
And after the ceremony, there's a feast.
我们结婚后，我就是你的
When we marry, I become yours.
永远都是
Forever.
不早了
It's getting late.
我该走了
I should go.
我能再来看你吗？
May I come and visit you again?
那好吧
All right, then.
记住…
Remember,
我们的小秘密
our little secret.
“詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士…
"Ser Jaime Lannister.
在16岁时被封骑士，并成为御林护卫
Knighted and named to the Kingsguard in his 16th year.
君临城沦陷时…
At the sack of King's Landing,
谋杀了他的国王伊里斯二世
murdered his king Aerys II.
被劳勃·拜拉席恩赦免
Pardoned by Robert Baratheon.
因此得名‘弑君者’”
Thereafter known as the Kingslayer."
填写这些书页是指挥官的职责
It's the duty of the Lord Commander to fill those pages.
我的部分还有空可填
And there's still room left on mine.
瓦雷利亚钢
Valyrian steel.
嗯
Mmm.
给你了
It's yours.
我不能接受
I can't accept this.
它由奈德·史塔克的剑重铸而来
It was reforged from Ned Stark's sword.
你要用它保护奈德·史塔克的女儿
You'll use it to defend Ned Stark's daughter.
你向她们的母亲起誓带回史塔克家的姑娘们
You swore an oath to return the Stark girls to their mother.
史塔克夫人死了
Lady Stark's dead.
艾莉亚可能也死了
Arya's probably dead, too,
但还有机会找到珊莎并带她去安全的地方
but there's still a chance to find Sansa and get her somewhere safe.
我还有东西给你
I've got something else for you.
希望是你的尺寸
I hope I got your measurements right.
我会找到她
I'll find her.
为了凯特琳夫人
For Lady Catelyn.
也为了你
And for you.
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
我还有一样礼物
I have one more gift.
我不需要侍从
I don't need a squire.
你当然需要
Of course you do.
他会拖累我的
He'll slow me down.
我弟弟亏欠他的，他在这里不安全
My brother owes him a debt. He's not safe here.
你保证他安全，这就是骑士精神
You're keeping him from harm. It's chivalry.
我不会拖累你的，爵士…
I won't slow you down, ser--
夫人
my lady.
我保证，我会好好服侍你
I promise I'll serve you well.
瞧？小伙子不错的，你们会和睦的
See? He's a good lad. You'll get along.
提利昂大人的礼物
Compliments of Lord Tyrion.
他在黑水河之战的斧头
His axe from the Blackwater.
你还等什么，亲一下？
What are you waiting for, a kiss?
给女士备马
Ready the lady's horse.
他们说最好的剑都有名号
They say the best swords have names.
想好了吗？
Any ideas?
守誓剑
Oathkeeper.
再见，布蕾妮
Good-bye, Brienne.
快，快走
Come on, move.
我不该带她走的
I should never have taken her away.
- 她在这里不安全 - 她在那里也不安全
- She wasn't safe here. - She's not safe out there.
我早该知道
I should have known.
你说过长城以南有野人
You told us there were wildlings south of the Wall.
他们如果袭击小村庄，鼹鼠村可能就是下一个
If they're raiding the smaller villages, Mole's Town could be next.
- 下一个可能是黑城堡 - 我要回去找吉莉
- Castle Black could be next. - I should go back for Gilly.
我们有命令，不许离开城堡
We have orders. No one's to leave the castle.
我记得你曾违反命令，南下帮助罗柏
I remember when you disobeyed orders and rode south to help Robb.
我还记得是谁追上我把我带回家
And I remember who came after me and brought me home.
我知道不容易，山姆，相信我
I know how hard it is, Sam, believe me.
当你告诉我布兰去了塞外…
When you told me about Bran going beyond the Wall,
我一心只想等我身体恢复…
all I could think about was getting my strength back
出去找到他
so I could go and find him.
但愿我当时能说服他跟我回来
I wish I could have convinced him to come back with me.
我试过了，真的
I tried. Really, I did.
他们能走多快？
How fast could they travel?
一个瘸小孩被一个傻子用雪橇拖着
A crippled boy being pulled on a sledge by a simpleton?
不知道
I don't know.
他们会经过野人村落
They'd pass wildling villages.
他们会找到落脚的地方
They could try to find shelter at one of them.
野人都加入了曼斯的队伍
The wildlings have joined up with Mance.
村落或落脚点都没人了
Every village or sheltered place will be deserted.
除非…
Except...
卡斯特堡？
Craster's?
你认为布兰可能找到…
You think Bran might have found--
雪诺
Snow.
我无意打扰
I don't mean to interrupt.
索恩想见你
Thorne wants to see you.
你要偷袭卡斯特堡垒…
Your foray to Craster's Keep,
我同意
I'll sanction it.
但我不会命令任何人跟你去
But I won't order anyone to go with you.
只许带志愿者
Volunteers only.
谢谢你，艾里沙爵士
Thank you, Ser Alliser.
弟兄们
Ahem, brothers.
我要去塞外的卡斯特堡垒
I'm going beyond the Wall to Craster's Keep.
我要抓住据守在那里的叛徒，或者杀了他们
I'm going to capture the mutineers holed up there or kill them.
我在找志愿者跟我一起去
I'm asking for volunteers to come with me.
这里到卡斯特堡是60里荒野
There's 60 miles of wilderness between here and Craster's
曼斯·雷德的军队正快速逼近
and Mance Rayder has an army bearing down on us,
但我们必须去
but we have to do this.
我们的存亡取决于…
Our survival may depend on
我们能否在曼斯之前找到这些叛徒
us getting to these mutineers before Mance does.
他们了解长城，他们了解我们的防御
They know the Wall. They know our defenses.
如果曼斯知道这些，我们就完了
If Mance learns what they know, we're lost.
如果这些还不够…
But if that's not enough,
那么再想一下
then consider this.
如果守夜人真的是兄弟…
If the Night's Watch are truly brothers,
莫尔蒙司令官就是我们的父亲
then Lord Commander Mormont was our father.
他的生与死都是为了守夜人…
He lived and died for the Watch
却被自己人背叛
and he was betrayed by his own men.
被懦夫从背后刺死
Stabbed in the back by cowards.
他不该落得如此下场
He deserved far better.
现在我们可以为他雪耻
All we can give him now is justice.
谁愿意跟我一起？
Who will join me?
我不能让新兵去塞外
I can't let a recruit come north of the Wall.
那就让我宣誓
Then let me say my vows.
如果你要去战斗…
If it's a fight you're heading for,
你需要能打的人
then you need men who know how.
谢谢，兄弟们
Thank you, brothers.
不，不要
No, don't.
不要，求求你
Don't, please.
求求你不要！
Please don't. Ow!
你弄痛我了
You're hurting me.
来自杜松子巷的卡尔·制革匠…
Karl Tanner from Gin Alley
喝酒用的是…
drinking wine from the skull
该死的杰奥·莫尔蒙的头骨
of Jeor fucking Mormont.
有什么命令，司令官大人？
Any command for us, Lord Commander?
你说什么？
What's that?
把他们操到死？
Fuck 'em till they're dead?
你们听到了，孩子们
Did you hear that, boys?
把他们操到死
Fuck 'em till they're dead.
雷斯特
Rast.
出去给野兽喂食
Go outside and feed the beast.
我们应该杀了那东西
We should kill that thing.
你应该闭上你的臭嘴…
You should shut your fucking hole,
丑陋的烂逼
ugly little cunt.
你长得像他妈蛋蛋皮
You look like a fucking ballsack.
丑逼，看你那张逼脸
Ugly. Look at your stupid cunt face.
我一泡尿淹死5个你这样的
I could piss in any gutter and soak five of you.
你知道我在君临杀一个多少钱？
Know how much they paid me to kill a man in King's Landing?
7个银币
Seven silvers.
他们告诉我那人的名字，他就活不过天亮
They told me a man's name and that man never saw daylight again.
那些笨蛋都逃不出我的魔掌
None of them cocksuckers got away from me.
9岁以后就没打输过
Haven't lost a fight since I was nine.
也许该输一次了
Maybe it's time.
你说呢，嗯？
What do you think, eh?
也许就是你
Maybe you're the man.
嗯，逼人？
Eh, cunt?
我连毛都摸不到
I wouldn't stand a chance.
我们都不行
None of us would.
在杜松子巷我是个传奇
I was a fucking legend in Gin Alley.
他妈的传奇！
A fucking legend!
我可以打败骑士…
I would take any knight--
任何骑士，在任何时候
any knight, any time.
傻逼们穿着盔甲，他妈的胆小鬼
Fucking cunts in steel plate. Fucking cowards.
- 给诸神的礼物 - 给诸神的礼物
- A gift for the gods. - A gift for the gods.
给诸神的礼物
A gift for the gods.
那他妈是什么？
What the fuck is that?
卡斯特最后一个孩子，男孩
Craster's last child. A boy.
我拿他怎么办？
What am I supposed to do with him?
卡斯特拿他们怎么办？
What did Craster do with 'em?
趁还没长大杀了他们，对他也一样？
Kill 'em before they could grow up and do the same to him?
好吧
All right.
不需要多一张吃饭的嘴
Don't need another mouth to feed.
- 把他给我 - 他没杀他们
- Hand him over. - He didn't kill them.
- 他献出他们 - 给谁？
- He offered them. - To who?
给诸神
To the gods.
异鬼
The white walkers.
给诸神的礼物 给诸神的礼物
A gift for the gods. A gift for the gods.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
行…
So...
如果他觉得这样好…
if it worked for him...
就给异鬼吧
Let's give the walkers what they want.
雷斯特正要去那边
Rast is headed that way.
红眼的混蛋
Pink-eyed fuck.
你渴了？
You thirsty?
我操！
Fuck!
阿多
Hodor.
你们听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
是个婴儿吗？
Is that a baby?
要来了
It's coming.
我要过去
I'm going out there.
不行，我们要待在一起
No, we need to stay together.
我要去
I'm going.
- 布兰，布兰 - 阿多，阿多
- Bran. Bran. - Hodor. Hodor.
- 阿多 - 布兰，怎么了？
- Hodor. - Bran, what happened?
夏天，它受伤了，他们用陷阱抓住了他
Summer, he's hurt. They've caught him in a trap.
谁？
Who?
没看到，但他们关着我哥哥的狼
I didn't see, but they have my brother's wolf.
他们关着白灵
They have Ghost.
他们是守夜人
They're Night's Watch.
瞧
Look.
琼恩也许在这里
Jon might be here.
如果琼恩在，他们为什么把他的狼关着？
If Jon was here, why would they put his wolf in a cage?
曾经是守夜人，不再是了
They might have been Night's Watch once, not anymore.
这里不安全，我们得走了
We're not safe here. We need to go.
不行
No.
布兰，我们得走了
Bran, we need to go now.
我不能丢下夏天
I'm not leaving without Summer.
你记得笼子在哪吗？
Can you remember where the cage was?
在堡垒的东边
The east side of the keep.
如果我没回来，我们在…
If I'm not back soon, we'll meet--
阿多
Hodor.
阿多，阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
阿多
Hodor.
我有你这么壮，我他妈就是国王了
If I was your size, I'd be king of the fucking world.
扶他起来
Help him up.
不错啊
This is nice.
上好的皮子
Fine leather.
你不是野人
You're no wildling.
是要人，是贵族
Important. Highborn.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你瞧，在我的家乡…
You see, where I come from,
我这样的普通人扇了你这样的小少爷
a commoner like me slaps a little lord like you,
我会失去右手
I'd lose my right hand.
但我们离家太远了，对吗？
But we're a long way from home, aren't we?
你们两个
And the two of you,
长相怪异，在长城之外…
fancy-looking folks north of the Wall
树林里游荡
creeping through the woods.
是不是有点怪？
Isn't that a bit odd?
我喜欢你的卷发
I like your curly hair.
我妈妈也有这样的卷发
My mom had curls like that.
漂亮的棕色卷发
Beautiful brown curls.
为什么你们拖着一个瘸小子跑这么远？
Why'd you drag a crippled boy all the way up here?
看来你们还没玩过这游戏
See you haven't played this game before.
贵族人质…
A highborn hostage,
很值钱
that's valuable.
但你们三个…
But three of them,
要吃很多东西
that's a lot of mouths to feed.
他是什么毛病？
What the fuck's wrong with him?
过来
Come here.
不，求你
No, please.
求你，求你，让我救他
Please. Please, let me help him.
- 你们是谁？ - 求你
- Who are you? - Pleas.
- 你们是谁？ - 我是布兰登·史塔克
- Who are you? - I'm Brandon Stark!
我是临冬城的布兰登·史塔克
I'm Brandon Stark of Winterfell.
是琼恩·雪诺的弟弟
It's Jon Snow's brother.
我是梅拉，我是梅拉，我在这里
It's Meera. It's Meera. I'm right here.
我还以为今天又是无聊的一天
And I thought this was gonna be another boring day.
我在这里
I'm right here.